

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Târgu-Mureş, str. Aleea Covasna 9/13, Romania

□ (+40) 764 325 745 | Servin_szilagyi@outlook.com | Arenyoke.github.io/site/ | Oernyoke | Servin-szilagyi | Servin_szilagyi@outlook.com



Summary_

Experienced developer having a wide interest in distributed back-end systems, decoupled front-ends and cloud based technologies.

Skills_

Programming Java, C\C++, C#, JavaScript, TypeScript, Kotlin, Python

Markup HTML5, CSS3, LESS, SASS

Frameworks Spring/Spring Boot, Angular JS/Angular 2.x and above, Qt, Android, NodeJS

Query languages SQL, PL\SQL - Oracle, MongoDB, ElasticSearch

Others Strong algorithmic skills tested on interviews at Google, Microsoft, AWS, Revolut, etc.

Spoken languages English, Hungarian, Romanian

Work Experience

RIA Solutions Group Târgu-Mures, Romania

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER / TEAM LEAD

September 2019 - PRESENT

- Participate in development of cloud based solutions for clients from the logistics industry.
- Apply domain driven design principles to implement new libraries using micro-service architecture.
- Implement and maintain multiple services using both event sourcing (Apache Kafka) and REST APIs as a way of communication. The stack of technologies used for service development includes languages which run on JVM, Java 8 and Groovy with usage of Spring Boot and other Spring libraries (Spring MVC, Spring Data, Spring AOC, Spring Batch etc.). It also includes NodeJS with the usage of JavaScript ES6 features.
- Develop and integrate several features which required handling both relational and non-relational data. The technology stack implies heavy usage of Elasticsearch for indexing and searching huge amount of client data. Besides, several services use MySQL/MariaDB databases for relational data and Apache Cassandra database for non relational data.
- · Work with real-time data streams using Amazon SQS and big data processing using Spring Batch.
- Participate in front-end development as well, implementing several features visible to the end user. The front-end stack implies usage of HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript with the usage of AngularJS framework.
- Practice test driven development (TDD), implement unit tests/integration tests for code changes where testing was feasible. Have in-depth experience with Spock framework, as well with JUnit4 and Mochito.
- Work in agile framework, collaborating with the client and business in story grooming, reviewing story/acceptance criteria and performance metrics
- Participate in interviewing new software engineer candidates.
- Provide mentorship and guidance for new joiners and junior colleagues.

Endava RomaniaTârgu-Mureş, Romania

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

August 2017 - September 2019

- Develop and maintain multiple full-stack business applications, working in agile teams. During my work the following technologies were used:
 - Back-end based on Java stack: Java 8, Maven, JAX-WS, JAX-RS, Spring/Spring Boot (Spring Core, Spring MVC, Spring AOP, Spring Security, Spring Data, Spring Batch, Spring Test), Tomcat, JBoss;
 - Persistence: extensively used both SQL (Oracle database with Spring Data on top of Hibernate JPA, Liquibase for migrations) and noSQL type databases (MarkLogic 8 with JSON documents. For interaction/querying we used server side Javascript);
 - Front-end: AngularJS (which implies heavy usage of Javascript[ES5])/Angular 4 (TypeScript), HTML5, CSS3 (Sass) + Twitter Bootstrap 3, package-managers (npm, Bower);
 - Deployment/DevOps: Jenkins, Docker, Maven, Grunt, Gulp, npm;
 - Testing/Unit testing frameworks: JUnit, Mockito, Karma, Jasmin, Protractor;
 - Other libraries/frameworks: Google Guava, Apache commons, Lombok, Dozer mapper, Querydsl, MapStruct, Iodash.
- · Gather requirements from the external clients, actively participate in client and internal agile meetings.
- Develop REST based Web Services used by third-parties and implement REST end-points.
- · Secure REST end-points using Spring Security. Write and generate documentation for these end-points using Swagger.
- $\bullet \ \ \ \ \, \text{Initiate extensive refactorings of older functionalities, focus on usage of design patterns.}$
- Integrate with the external services which were exposing both REST and SOAP end-points.
- · Create user friendly GUIs using HTML5, CSS3 and Javascript, implement single-page front-end applications using Angular.
- Extensively involved in code reviews (platforms used: BitBucket, Gerrit).
- Actively involved in release management/product delivery (platforms used: Amazon EC, Amazon S3).
- · Participate in summer internship as a trainer/interviewer. Supervise their work, give guidance when it's needed.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER May 2015 - July 2017

- Develop and maintain a Railway Automation project using C++ (MFC, Boost), Visual Basic and Python environments.
- · Work in a regulated environment, the components developed by us where graded between SIL 0 and SIL 2 safety-integrity level.
- Develop and maintain unit tests using GTEST and GMOCK libraries.
- Implement regression and UI tests using AutoIT and Python languages.
- Configure and maintain Jenkins continuous integration system, develop batch scripts for automatic builds.
- · Write software documentation (use cases, release notes) and testing documentation (test cases).
- Actively collaborate with clients and other teams.
- · Actively attend Scrum meetings.
- Supervise summer internship attendees.
- Other technologies used: IBM Rational Synergy (version control system), IBM Rational Doors (software documentation), PVCS Merant Tracker (bugs and tickets), Citrix, Oracle Virtual Box (virtualization and working remotely on the client's network), AutoIT (used for UI and regression/integration testing), Parasoft Static Analysis for C and C++.

Smartsoft (now 3SS)

Târqu-Mures, Romania

ANDROID DEVELOPER INTERN

July 2014 - August 2014

• Develop the timetable part for a VOD and streaming application for Android.

evoline (now Accenture Industrial Software Solutions)

Târgu-Mureş, Romania

June 2013 - July 2013

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT INTERN

• Develop a small application in C# working in a small team.

- $\bullet \ \ \, \text{Use multiply version control systems } git, svn \text{ and write a summary comparing the version control systems used in the development process}.$
- Make a short demo accomplished work at the ending of the internship period.

Education.

Sapientia Hungarian University of Transylvania

Târgu-Mureş, Romania

MASTER'S DEGREE IN SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT

September 2015 - June 2017

- Studied: Agile Methodologies, Numerical Math and Statistics, Virtual Reality and Game Development, Genetic Algorithms, Concurrent Computing (CUDA), Distributed Systems (Java EE), Software Verification and Synthesis, Software Testing, Modern Databases, Component Based Software Development
- Final grade: 10/10
- Thesis: Parallel artistic style transfer using deep convolutional neural network

Sapientia Hungarian University of Transylvania

Târgu-Mureş, Romania

BACHELOR'S DEGREE IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

September 2011 - June 2015

- Algorithms and Data Structures, Programming Languages, Web Technologies, Operating Systems, Databases, Computer Networks, Distributed Systems, Artificial Intelligence, Object Oriented Programming, Java Technologies, Android Programming, Image Processing, Computer Architecture, Assembly Programming, Micro controllers, Programmable Digital Systems, Digital Signal Processing
- Final grade: 10/10
- · Thesis: WLAN based conference system
- Honors:
 - 16th Scientific Student Conference of Technical Science XVI. Műszaki Erdélyi Tudományos Diakköri Konferencia, Second place in Computer Science and Applied Informatics section with the project of: "WLAN based Conference System
 - XIV Scientific Students' Associations Conference XIV. Tudományos Diákköri Konferencia (Sapientia TDK), First place in Computer Science and Software Development Section section with the project of: "WLAN based Conference System"

Certificates

Oracle Certified Professional: Java 11 Developer

Since January 2021

ORACLE

https://www.youracclaim.com/badges/d24ba586-7589-488b-ac86-2b5ae49e994a/public_url

AWS Certified Developer - Associate

Since February 2021

AMAZON WEB SERVICES

https://www.youracclaim.com/badges/d507de98-aa20-425b-9211-15b4918c5308/public_url

Microsoft Certified: Azure Developer Associate

Since October 2020

MICROSOFT

https://www.youracclaim.com/badges/93829fc2-5ed8-4bf6-9291-5912ac66af7f/public_url

Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals

Since September 2020

Microsof

https://www.youracclaim.com/badges/3e2a89c1-0ef3-4a45-9e22-ccd54ac6e0ef/public_url

Scrum, Kanban, Lean and Story Writing

Since September 2016

SPRINT CONSULTING LLC

Cambridge English: First

Since July 2016

CAMBRIDGE ENGLISH LANGUAGE ASSESSMENT

-

Software Security - License AFRP6UPJZ5

Since September 2015

COURSERA VERIFIED CERTIFICATES

https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/verify/AFRP6UPJZ5

Programming Mobile Applications for Android Handheld Systems - License U4KVNZF6NS

Since September 2014

COURSERA VERIFIED CERTIFICATES

https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/verify/U4KVNZF6NS